Max Z. Gu

Page 1/2

100 Tunney's Pasture Dr., Ottawa ON K1A 0T6 (613)601-1111 zgu6@my.centennialcollge.ca

PROFILE

Experienced and driven **Software Developer** with the success of large-scale complex enterprise software, mobile applications, and web applications with 16 years of hands-on experience. Looking to bring my enthusiasm, passion, expertise, and strong team ethic to your team.

SKILLS

- Java SE/EE, .NET, C#, VB, C/C++, Assembly, Fortran, Python, MVC, Entity Framework
- Apple iOS Development on XCODE/Object C
- Android mobile development on Android Studio
- Native mobile development and cross-platform framework Apache Cordova
- Web application in PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Hibernate, RESTful
- Enterprise applications architecture and algorithm design, system analysis, coding, and testing
- Operating System level development/debugging at registers level
- Relational database MS-SQL, Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL and NoSQL MongoDB
- Solid knowledge on business finance, taxes, financial reporting, and bookkeeping
- Agile development, leadership, interpersonal and communication skills
- Troubleshooting, supervising, customer support and problem-solving skills

EDUCATION

University of Toronto, Ontario, Canada

2004-2008

Honours Bachelor of Computer Science

- Software Engineering stream
- Enhanced OS/SYS161 Operating System Linux Kernel in memory and file management
- Developed P2P WAN File Sharing System TCP/IP (Napster-like system)

Fanshawe College, London, Ontario, Canada

2019-2021

Business Finance, 2 Years Full-time Online, College Diploma

- Financial Management, Tax and Retirement Planning
- Insurance, Investments, and Estate Planning

Algonquin College, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

2018-2019

Business Accounting, 2 Years Full-time Online, College Diploma

- Financial Accounting and Reporting
- Accounting Software QuickBooks, Profile, UFile, and Sage 50
- Income Tax for Corporations, Cost/Managerial Accounting, Bookkeeping

WORK EXPERIENCE

Statistics Canada (Ottawa, Canada)

Programmer Analyst

September 2008 – August 2021

- Successfully delivered ASP.NET websites used by 10,000+ users
- Migrated legacy systems to the modern design of ASP.NET MVC VB/C#, PHP
- Established requirements gathering, meeting clients, data modeling, business process modeling, business object modeling, and user interface design; Planned, scheduled, guided, and executed systems analysis and functional design activities

2004 200

nent

Page 2/2

iOS Developer

September 2008 – April 2010

- iOS apps on iOS/XCODE/Object C/Apache Cordova/Native applications
- iPhone game iBoxes, top 50 daily sales out of 15000+ applications in 2009

IBM Toronto Software Lab (Toronto, Canada)

Application and Integration Middleware Software, XL C/C++/Fortran Compiler

Compiler Validation Specialist

September 2007-August 2008

- Created specification, design, test cases and automation test scripts for new compiler features
- Kicked off test run regularly for various platforms, including UNIX AIX and Linux SUSE, and investigated problems that may occur during the runs on Supercomputers Power serials
- Participated in peer reviews of other developers' designs and test case source codes

Compiler Front End Software Developer

May 2006-September 2007

- Created code and unit tests for new compiler features.
- Investigated methods to improve functionality and performance of the XL C/C++/Fortran Frontend and Runtime components, and shared the methods with other team members
- Helped the team to win the rank 1 Fortran compiler in the world conference in 2007 for XL Fortran Compiler V12.0
- Involved algorithm and data structure design, implementation of new features of XL Compilers in lower-level internal programming language and Assembly Language
- Helped other developers of diagnosis of compilation failures and performance improvement, as well as debugging of failing test cases
- Created Perl/Python/Shell scripts and tools to improve the automated build and test, and participated in peer reviews of other developers' designs

NorthPoint Micro Services (Toronto, Canada) Software Developer

May 2005-February 2006

- Involved in user requirements analysis, high level design, state transition diagram and flowcharts
- Developed PaperBuster, an OCR document management standalone application, client/server version on VB.net and MS SQL Server
- Enhanced system performance significantly by creating a new traverse algorithm in nodes trees for massive documents management

REFERENCES

Available upon request